Finding Aid for Carl Cohen papers, 1950-2012
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Topical and Name files
  - Program in Human Values in Medicine 1985-1996
    - Conference on Ethics, Humanism and Medicine
      - 1982-1991, 16 folders (Box 57)
      - 1993 (Box 57)
    - Consider magazine (pornography) 1990 (Box 57)
    - Coon, William 1993 (Box 57)
    - Cureton, Cathy 1986 (Box 57)
    - Daniels, Marsha 1985 (Box 57)
    - DaRif, Craig 1988 (Box 57)
    - Data conversion 1986 (Box 57)
    - Davidson College colloquium 1992 (Box 57)
    - Davies, Terence 1986, 2 folders (Box 57)
    - Davis, Bernard 1989 (Box 57)
    - Davis, Wayne (Box 57)
    - Discussion groups 1987 (Box 57)
    - Eagle, Herbert 1988 (Box 58)
    - Eisenberg, Rebecca 1986 (Box 58)
    - Elkins, Thomas 1987-1990, 3 folders (Box 58)
    - Engineering seminar 1985 (Box 58)
    - Ensminger, William 1987 (Box 58)
    - Ethical issues in the future of medicine 1987 (Box 58)
    - Ethics Committee, 3 folders (Box 58)
    - Ethics, Public Policy Center (Box 58)
    - Euthanasia symposium 1993 (Box 58)
    - Ewing case review 1986 (Box 58)
    - Family Practice Dept. 1985-1986, 3 folders (Box 58)
    - Farley, Reynolds 1989 (Box 58)
    - Felt, Kay 1986 (Box 58)
    - Filing systems 1995 (Box 58)
    - Fine, Eve (Box 58)
    - Fitzgerald, Tom 1990 (Box 58)
    - Fleck, Leo 1992 (Box 58)
    - Foley, Barbara 1986 (Box 58)
    - Forsyth, John 1985 (Box 58)
    - Fort Wayne Medical Society 1984 (Box 58)
    - Forums on classified research 1986 (Box 58)
    - Four Systems 1987 (Box 58)
    - Free speech 1988 (Box 58)
    - Freeport Clinic 1991 (Box 58)
    - Gardner, Chad, 2 folders (Box 58)
    - Gastroenterology ethics 1986 (Box 58)
    - Geller, Brad 1992 (Box 58)
    - Genetics (Ethical issues in genetics) 1985-1986, 2 folders (Box 58)
    - Gerontology grant 1985 (Box 58)
    - Goldman, David 1991 (Box 58)
    - Goldman, Edward, 4 folders (Box 58)
    - Goldstein, Irwin, 2 folders (Box 58)
    - Gorovitz, Samuel 1984, 2 folders (Box 58)
    - Govier, Trudy 1987 (Box 58)
    - Grand Hotel 1989 (Box 58)
    - Grand Rounds, presentation 1985, 2 folders (Box 58)
    - Grant request, Biomedical Research Council 1987 (Box 58)
    - Green, Robert 1989, 3 folders (Box 58)
    - Greenfield, Lazar 1988 (Box 58)
    - Grekin, Roger 1989 (Box 58)
    - Grimberg, Joseph 1986 (Box 58)
    - Grimberg, Sharon 1987 (Box 58)
    - Hanauske-Abel, Hartmut 1986 (Box 58)
    - Hastings Center 1988-1989, 6 folders (Box 58)
    - Heart Association 1985 (Box 58)
    - Heflin, Howell 1989 (Box 58)
    - Hemlock Society 1990 (Box 58)
    - Henckley, Karen 1986 (Box 58)
    - Henley, Keith 1985 (Box 58)
    - Hippocratic oath and nuclear war 1986 (Box 58)
    - Hooghart, Anne, 3 folders (Box 58)
    - Hourani, Ben 1989 (Box 58)
    - Howell, Joel 1994, 2 folders (Box 58)
    - Human Values Teaching programs 1985, 3 folders (Box 58)
    - Humana Corporation 1989 (Box 58)
    - Hurst, Steven (Box 58)
    - Illinois Institute of Technology 1987 (Box 58)
    - Institute for Human Gene Therapy 1975 (Box 58)
    - Inteflex, 2 folders (Box 58)
    - Internal medicine 1985 (Box 58)
    - Intephase 1985-1986, 1989, 2 folders (Box 58)
    - Institutional review board 1985 (Box 58)
    - Jackson, Marion 1986 (Box 58)
    - Jaeger, Jeanne 1985 (Box 58)
    - Japan, ethics and medicine, Nihon University 1985 (Box 58)
    - Johnson, Joseph 1987 (Box 58)
    - Johnson, Sally 1991 (Box 58)
    - Johnson Foundation (Box 58)
    - Jones, David 1989-1990 (Box 59)
    - Jorgens, Elisabeth (Box 59)
    - Journal of Medicine and Philosophy 1977 (Box 59)
    - Journal of the American Medical Association 1990 (Box 59)
    - Kaplan, Alex 1994 (Box 59)
    - Kauffman, Carol 1990 (Box 59)
    - Kelch, Robert 1990, 2 folders (Box 59)
    - Kelley, Bill 1986 (Box 59)
    - Kennedy, Edward 1988 (Box 59)
    - Kennedy Institute of Ethics 1985, 3 folders (Box 59)
    - Kheterpal, Vik 1985 (Box 59)
    - Kindt, Glen (Box 59)
    - Knudsen, Terrie 1985 (Box 59)
    - Krause, Charles 1988 (Box 59)
    - Koop, C. Everett 1988 (Box 59)
    - La Puma, John 1992 (Box 59)
    - Labun, Carol 1985 (Box 59)
    - Lansing Area Advocate for Choice 1990 (Box 59)
    - Lantos, Tom 1989 (Box 59)
    - Legal references in Medical Education 1986 (Box 59)
    - Leiser, Burt 1979 (Box 59)
    - Levin, Carl 1986 (Box 59)
    - Levy, Bob 1987, 2 folders (Box 59)
    - Lindenauer, Marty 1985-1986 (Box 59)
    - Linn, Ruth (1986 (Box 59)
    - Literature, Science, and the Arts ethics request (Box 59)
    - Loomis, Shelly 1985 (Box 59)
    - MABRC (Midwest AIDS Biobehavioral Resource Center) 1987 (Box 59)
    - Maguire, Dan (Box 59)
    - Margolis seminar 1987 (Box 59)
    - Margolis, Lew (drug companies) 1986 (Box 59)
    - Marshall, Norman 1987 (Box 59)
    - Mead, James 1991 (Box 59)
    - Medical activities, 1984- (Box 59)
    - Medical Center Alumni Society 1987 (Box 59)
    - Medical Center development 1994 (Box 59)
    - Medical School, 2 folders (Box 59)
    - Medical School panel 1994 (Box 59)
    - MERN (Medical Ethics Resource Network) 1987 (Box 59)
    - Miller, Ann 1987 (Box 59)
    - Momentum 1993 (Box 59)
    - Morley, George 1986 (Box 59)
    - Murphy, Kevin 1991 (Box 59)
    - National Science Foundation 1986, 2 folders (Box 59)
    - Natural Resources, School of 1986 (Box 59)
    - Near death (Wiseman) (Box 59)
    - NEH 1988, 3 folders (Box 59)
    - Neidhardt, Fred 1985 (Box 59)
    - New England Journal of Medicine, 4 folders (Box 59)
    - Niederhuber, John 1985 (Box 59)
    - Noise 1992 (Box 59)
    - Nurses (transplant symposium) 1990 (Box 59)
    - Nursing 1992 (Box 59)
    - Nutrition conference 1986 (Box 59)
    - OB/GYN (Tom Elkins) 1986 (Box 59)
    - Office space (Box 59)
    - Office of Technical Assessment 1990 (Box 59)
    - Ombudspanel 1991 (Box 59)
    - Opheal scan (sample) (Box 59)
    - Orlando schedule 1991 (Box 59)
    - Orthodontists 1989, 2 folders (Box 59)
    - Osborn June, 1986 (Box 59)
    - Patent office 1988 (Box 59)
    - Payne, Peter 1992 (Box 59)
    - Payton, Sallyanne 1988 (Box 59)
    - Pearlman, Mark 1990 (Box 59)
    - Pellegrino, Edmund 1987 (Box 59)
    - Pennsylvania, University of 1986 (Box 59)
    - Photos (Box 59)
    - Price, Alan 1990, 2 folders (Box 59)
    - Program in Human Values in Medicine, 3 folders (Box 59)
    - Psychiatry 1993 (Box 59)
    - Psychological Association 1992 (Box 59)
    - Pursell, Carl 1986 (Box 59)
    - Quality of patient's life 1985 (Box 59)
    - Quigg, Donald 1988 (Box 59)
    - Relman, Arnold, 7 folders (Box 59)
    - Ringler, Daniel 1990 (Box 59)
    - Riverside Methodist Hospitals 1991 (Box 59)
    - Rodriguez, Lorna 1985 (Box 59)
    - Rosenthal, Marilynn, 2 folders (Box 59)
    - Sabbatical letters 1989 (Box 59)
    - Salon lecture 1992 (Box 59)
    - Schwartz, John 1987 (Box 60)
    - Schwartz, Stan 1987 (Box 60)
    - Sederburg, William 1987, 2 folders (Box 60)
    - Shapira, Amos 1987, 2 folders (Box 60)
    - Sheagren, John, 8 folders (Box 60)
    - Simmonds, Richard 1990 (Box 60)
    - Singapore, University of 1986 (Box 60)
    - Singer, Beth 1988 (Box 60)
    - Singer, Dale Anne, 3 folders (Box 60)
    - Smith, Gary 1990 (Box 60)
    - Smith, Kate Stolp (Box 60)
    - Smoker skit 1987 (Box 60)
    - Social Work, School of 1988 (Box 60)
    - Stell, Lance 1987 (Box 60)
    - Steneck, Nick, 2 folders (Box 60)
    - Strasbourg 1988, 2 folders (Box 60)
    - Surger residents 1990 (Box 60)
    - Swain, Hank 1990 (Box 60)
    - Swartz, Martha 1990 (Box 60)
    - Taren, James, 7 folders (Box 60)
    - Taubman Library 1986 (Box 60)
    - Teaching values 1987, 2 folders (Box 60)
    - Threatt, Barbara 1986 (Box 60)
    - Transplant, alcoholics 1990 (Box 60)
    - Trester, Kenneth 1986 (Box 60)
    - Turck, John 1988 (Box 60)
    - UCLA codes 1985 (Box 60)
    - Uhlmann, Wendy 1987, 2 folders (Box 60)
    - Umbrella committee 1992 (Box 60)
    - van der Spek, Abraham 1989 (Box 60)
    - Velleman, David 1985 (Box 60)
    - Vilardell, Francisco 1987 (Box 60)
    - Vita, 3 folders (Box 60)
    - Ward, Peter (abortion) 1985 (Box 60)
    - Warner-Lambert, 2 folders (Box 60)
    - Washtenaw County Medical Society 1987 (Box 60)
    - Weisbach, Jerry, 2 folders (Box 60)
    - Weisberg, Roger (health care film) 1986, 2 folders (Box 60)
    - Western Michigan University 1990 (Box 60)
    - Whitehouse, Frank 1992, 2 folders (Box 60)
    - Wich, Ann (Box 60)
    - Wilkerson, Catherine 1992 (Box 60)
    - Wilson, Linda 1986, 2 folders (Box 60)
    - Witteveen, Gavin 1988 (Box 60)
    - Work, Bruce 1987 (Box 60)
    - Yamada, Tadataka 1992, 2 folders (Box 60)
    - Zuidema, George, 5 folders (Box 60)
    - Zweifler, Andy 1993 (Box 60)
- Publications
  - Published Articles
    (arranged in numbered sequence by CC in approximate reverse chronological order, 2005 to 1954)
    - "Aim for True Equality by Ending Preferences" Detroit Free Press, Op-Ed, Sunday, July 17, 2005 (Box 61)
      (article #1 missing)
    - "A Critique of the Alleged Moral Basis of Vegetarianism," A chapter in Food for Thought, ed. By Steve Sapontzis, Prometheus Books, 2004 (Box 61)
      (article #2 missing)
    - "Affirmative Action and Diversity" Commentary, Volume 117, No. 1, January 2004 (Box 61)
      (article #3 missing)
    - "Winks, Nods, Disguises -- and Racial Preference" Commentary, Volume 116, No. 2, September 2003 (Box 61)
      (article #4)
    - "Treating Animals Humanely; Obligations, Not Rights" The National Law Journal, 12 August 2002 (Box 61)
      (article #5 missing)
    - "About Personal Consequences in the Academy When a Professor Opposes Racial Preferences" Journal of Blacks in Higher Education, no. 34, Winter, 2002 (Box 61)
      (article #6)
    - "Race Preference and the Universities -- A Final Reckoning?" Commentary, Vol. 112, No. 2, September 2001 (Box 61)
      (article # 7)
    - Letters Commentary, Vol. 112, No. 5, December 2001 (Box 61)
      (article #7a)
    - "The Uses of Race in Admission under Regents v. Bakke" The Journal of Law in Society Wayne State University Law School Winter 1999, volume 1, no. 1, Detroit (Box 61)
      (article #8 missing)
    - "Preference by Race in University Admissions and the Quest for Diversity" The Journal of Urban and Contemporary Law, Vol. 54, 1998, Washington University School of Law (Box 61)
      (article #9)
    - "The Corruption that Is Group Preference," Academic Questions, Summer 1998 (Box 61)
      (article #10)
    - "Preference by Race is Neither Just nor Wise" Philosophic Exchange, State University of New York at Brockport, 1998 (Box 61)
      (article #11)
    - "Is Affirmative Action on the Way Out?" Commentary, Vol. 195, No. 3, March 1998 (Box 61)
      (article #12)
    - "Fears of Human Cloning are Without Merit" The Detroit News, March 4, 1998 (Box 61)
      (article #13 missing)
    - "Do Animals Have Rights?" Ethics and Behavior, Harvard University, Vol. 7, No. 2, pp. 91-102, 1997 (Box 61)
      (article #14)
    - "A Very Bad Compromise" The Journal of Blacks in Higher Education Spring, 1997 (Box 61)
      (article #15)
    - "The Equal Protection of the Laws" The Detroit News, December 28, 1997 (Box 61)
      (article #16 missing)
    - "Race in University of Michigan Admissions" The University of Michigan Record, Vol. 52, No. 23 February 25, 1997 (Box 61)
      (article #17)
    - "Affirmative Action and Racial Preference at the University of Michigan" in Declining Standards at Michigan Public Universities The Mackinac Center for Public Policy, February 1997 (Box 61)
      (article #18)
    - "Procreation After Death or Mental Incompetence" (with Dana A. Ohl, M.D., et al) Fertility and Sterility, Vol. 66, No. 6; December 1996 (Box 61)
      (article #19)
    - "Race, Lies, and Hopwood" Commentary, Vol. 101, No. 6, June 1996 (Box 61)
      (article #20)
    - Concerning Hopwood: A Reply to My Critics" Commentary, Vol. 102, No. 2, August 1996 (Box 61)
      (article #21 missing)
    - "Universities Abuse Admissions Powers" The Detroit News, Op-Ed, 31 March 1996 (Box 61)
      (article #22 missing)
    - Testimony before the U.S. House of Representatives, Committee on the Judiciary, Subcommittee on the Constitution, Washington, D.C., in support of the Equal Opportunity Act of 1995 December 7, 1995 Published in Congressional Digest, June-July 1996, Vol. 75, No. 6-7 (Box 61)
      (article #23)
    - "An Ethical Perspective on Animal Research" Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, Vol. 206, No. 4, February 15, 1995 (Box 61)
      (article #24)
    - "What Transplantation Can Teach Us about Health Care Reform" (with M. Benjamin and E. Grochowski) The New England Journal of Medicine, Vol. 330, 858-60 March 24, 1994 (Box 61)
      (article #25 missing)
    - "Ethical Aspects of Animal Research" in The Role of the Chimpanzee in Research, G. Eder, E. Kaiser, and F.A. King, eds., Karger Pub., Basel, 1994 (Box 61)
      (article #26)
    - "Accusations of Racism" The University Record, Ann Arbor, April 26, 1993 (Box 61)
      (article #27)
    - Notes from SGS Meeting 4/7/93 with Howard Schuman (Box 61)
      (article #27a)
    - "The Morality of Assisted Suicide" The Detroit Free Press, June 19, 1992, p. 13A (Box 61)
      (article #28)
    - "The Case for Presumed Consent to Transplant Human Organs After Death" Transplantion Proceedings, Vol. 24, No. 5 October 1992, pp. 2168-2172 (Box 61)
      (article #29)
    - "University Policy on Discriminatory Harassment" The University Record Ann Arbor, 9 November 1992 (Box 61)
      (article #30)
    - "The Penalty of Preference" The Michigan Daily, Ann Arbor, October 23, 1992 (Box 61)
      (article #31)
    - "Philosophical Issues in Regulating Biotechnology" Testimony in Proceedings of the Subcommittee on Technology, Committee on Science, Space, and technology, U.S. House of Representatives, December 6, 1991 (Box 61)
      (article #32)
    - "Politically Correct Language" Detroit News, November 14, 1991, p. 15A (Box 61)
      (article #33)
    - "The Morality of Transplantation," (letters to the editor with CC response to March 1991 article) Journal of the American Medical Association, Vol. 266, No. 2, July 10, 1991, pp. 213-214 (Box 61)
      (article #34)
    - "Alcoholics and Liver Transplantation," with Martin Benjamin Journal of the American Medical Association, Vol. 265, No. 10, March 13, 1991, pp. 1299-1301 (Box 61)
      (article #35)
    - "On the Ethics of Institutions" in Ethics and the Campus B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundation, Washington D.C., 1991 (Box 61)
      (article #36)
    - "Animal Experimentation Defended," in The Importance of Animal Experimentation for Safety and Biomedical Research, Kluwer Academic Publishers, Dordrecht, Netherlands, 1990, pp. 7-16 (Box 61)
      (article #37)
    - "How Not to Argue about Abortion," Michigan Quarterly Review, Vol. 29, No. 4, Fall, 1990, pp. 567-583 (Box 61)
      (article #38)
    - "Free Speech and Political Extremism: How Nasty Are We Free To Be?" Law and Philosophy 7, 1989, pp. 263-279 (Box 61)
      (article #39)
    - "Militant Morality: Civil Disobedience and Bioethics," Hastings Center Report, Vol. 19, No. 6, November 1989 (Box 61)
      (article #40)
    - "Roundtable Discussion: Patient Selection Criteria in Organ Transplantation: The Critical Questions" (Carl Cohen moderator) Transplantation Proceedings, Vol. 21, No. 3 June 1989 (Box 61)
      (article #41a)
    - "Anencephalic Infants as Sources of Transplantable Organs" with Martin Benjamin, et. al. Hastings Center Report, October / November 1988, pp. 28-30 (Box 61)
      (article #41)
    - "What is the Difference between an HIV and a CBC?" Hastings Center Report, August / September 1988, pp. 18-20 (Box 61)
      (article #42)
    - The Case for Federalism in Organ Sharing, with Martin Benjamin, et. al., published by the Transplant Policy Center, Ann Arbor, MI, 1987 (Box 61)
      (article #43)
    - "Heavy Question Arguments in Selected Issues in Logic and Communication," ed. By Trudy Govier, Wadworth Publishing Company, 1987 (Box 61)
      (article 43-a)
    - "The Case for the Use of Animals in Biomedical Research" New England Journal of Medicine 315: 865-870; October 2, 1986 (Box 61)
      (include letters to editor and CC's response in a subsequent issue; also letters sent to CC personally)
      (article #44)
    - "Naked Racial Preference" Commentary, Vol. 81, No. 3; March 1986 (Box 61)
      (article #45)
    - Letters to editor regarding "Naked Racial Preference" article Commentary, Vol. 82, No. 1, July 1986 (Box 61)
      (article #45a)
    - Review of Discrimination and Reverse Discrimination by Kent Greenawalt Law and Philosophy, Vol. 5, p. 135; 1986 (Box 61)
      (article #46)
    - "Should Mental Health Services be Rationed?: A Philosopher's Perspective" Administration in Mental Health, Vol. 13, No. 1, Fall 1985 (Box 61)
      (article #46-a)
    - "Philosophical Reflections on the Impact of Coronary Artery Surgery on Patients' Quality of Life" Quality of Life and Cardiovascular Care Vol. 1, No. 5; May 1985 (Box 61)
      (article #47)
    - "Technology and Political Freedom" in Technology and Freedom, Alfred Sloan Foundation, Davidson, N.C., March 1985 (Box 61)
      (article #48)
    - "Affirmative Action and the Rights of the Majority" in Minorities, Charles Fried, ed., Dahlem Konferenzen Springer Verlag, N.Y., Tokyo, Berlin, 1983 (Box 61)
      (article #49)
    - Introduction to John Dewey, The Middle Works, 1899-1924, Volume 15: 1923-1924, J.A. Boydston, ed., So. Illinois University Press, Carbondale, 1983 (Box 61)
      (article #50)
    - "Who's to the Left? What's to the Right?" Rackham Reports, Graduate School of Univ. of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Vol. 9, No. 1; Spring 1983 (Box 61)
      (article #51)
    - "On the Quality of Life" Circulation, Vol. 66, No. 5; November 1982, American Heart Association Monograph No. 92 (Box 61)
      (article #52)
    - "Affirmative Action in Medical School Admissions" in Troubling Problems in Medical Ethics, Alan R. Liss, N.Y., 1981 (Box 61)
      (article #53)
    - "Political Controversy and the University" in Public Policy in the 1980s, Southern University Conference Proceedings, N.R. Berte, ed., Savannah, 1980 (Box 61)
      (article #54)
    - "Political Controversy and the University" in Williams Reports, Williams College News Office, April 1983 (Box 61)
      (article #54a)
    - "Equality, Diversity, and Good Faith" Wayne Law Review, Vol. 26, No. 4; July 1980 (Box 61)
      (article #55)
    - "On the Right of the Patient to Know" Ethics, Humanism, and Medicine, M.D. Basson, ed., Alan R. Liss, Inc., N.Y., 1980 (Box 61)
      (article #56)
    - "Philosophy and Public Policy" Working Papers, The Rockefeller Foundation New York, October, 1980 (Box 61)
      (article #57)
    - "Divestiture and Apartheid" LSA Magazine, Vol. 3, No. 2, Ann Arbor, Winter 1980 (Box 61)
      (article #58)
    - "Fairness in Housing" Testimony before the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Committee on the Judiciary, United States Senate; Washington, D.C., September 17, 1979 published in Hearings on the Fair Housing Amendments Act, Washington, D.C., 1979, pp. 458-495 (Box 61)
      (article #59)
    - "Why Racial Preference is Illegal and Immoral" Commentary, Vol. 67, No. 6, pp. 40-52; June 1979 (Box 61)
      (article #60)
    - To the Subcommittee on the Constitution, September 17, 1979 (Box 61)
      (article #60a)
    - "Moral Issues in Medical Experimentation on Humans" Philosophic Exchange, Vol. 2, No. 5; Center for Philosophic Exchange, State University of New York at Brockport, N.Y., Summer 1979 (Box 61)
      (article #61)
    - "Justice Debased: The Weber Decision" Commentary, Vol. 68, No. 3, pp. 43-53; September 1979 (Box 61)
      (article #62)
    - Letters Commentary, Vol. 68, No. 5, November 1979 (Box 61)
      (article #62a)
    - "How Should We Decide Who Should Decide What Comes Before What?" Ethical Theory and Business, Beauchamp & Bowie, eds., Prentice Hall, Englewood Cliffs, 1979 (Box 61)
      (article #63)
    - "The ROTC and the University" The Michigan Alumnus, Ann Arbor, September 1979 (Box 61)
      (article #64)
    - "The Dangers of Inquiry and the Burden of Proof" Southern California Law Review, Vol. 51, No. 6, pp.1081-1113 September 1978 (Box 61)
      (article #65)
    - "The Case Against Group Libel" The Nation, Vol. 226, No. 24, June 24, 1978 (Box 61)
      (article #66)
    - "Medical Experimentation on Prisoners" Perspectives in Biology and Medicine, Vol. 21, No. 3, Spring 1978 (Box 61)
      (article #67)
    - "Medical Experimentation on Prisoners" From Medical Responsibility Paternalism, Informed Consent, and Euthanasia, The Humana Press, 1979 (Box 61)
      (article #67a)
    - "The Right to be Offensive: Skokie-The Extreme Test of Free Speech" The Nation, Vol. 226, No. 14, April 15, 1978 (Box 61)
      (article #68)
    - Letter The Nation, May 13, 1978 (Box 61)
      (article #68a)
    - "The Village of Skokie vs. Carl Cohen: An Exchange" The Nation, Vol. 226, No. 17, May 6, 1978 (Box 61)
      (article #69)
    - On Defending Free Speech (letter) The Nation, Vol. 227, No. 9, September 23, 1978 (Box 61)
      (article #69a)
    - "Race and Equal Protection of the Laws" Lincoln Law Review, Vol. X, No. 2, Fall 1977 (Box 61)
      (article #70)
    - "Who Are Equals?" The National Forum, Vol. 58, No. 1, Winter 1978 (Box 61)
      (article #71)
    - "When May Research Be Stopped?" The New England Journal of Medicine, 296: 1203-1210 May 26, 1977 (Box 61)
      (article #72)
    - "Racial Preference is Dynamite" The Chronicle of Higher Education, Vol. XIV, No. 10, May 2, 1977 (Box 61)
      (article #73)
    - "Ethnic Justice, Individual Rights" The Chronicle of Higher Education, Vol. XII, No. 1, March 1, 1976 (Box 61)
      (article #74)
    - "Revolutions and Copernican Revolutions" Science and Society, N.H. Steneck, ed., University of Michigan Press, Ann Arbor, 1975 (Box 61)
      (article #75)
    - "On The Child's Status in the Democratic State" Political Theory, Vol. 3, No. 4, November 1975 (Box 61)
      (article #76)
    - "Honorable Ends, Unsavory Means: Preferential Admission in Higher Education: The Civil Liberties Review, Vol. 2, No. 2, Spring 1975 (Box 61)
      (article #77)
    - "The Abuse of Morality: How Not to be Good" Moral Values in Contemporary Public Life, Marquette University, Milwaukee, 1975 (Box 61)
      (article #78)
    - "How Much Democracy for the University?" The Chronicle of Higher Education, Vol. XI, No. 5, October 14, 1975 (Box 61)
      (article #79)
    - "Race and the Constitution" The Nation, Vol. 220, No. 5, February 8, 1975 (Box 61)
      (article #80)
    - Democracy in Israel" The Nation, Vol. 219, No. 2, July 20, 1974 (Box 61)
      (article #81)
    - "The Health of the American Democratic System" Proceedings, National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council, New York, June 1974 (Box 61)
      (article #82)
    - "What, in Our House?" The Nation, Vol. 217, No. 21, December 17, 1973 (Box 61)
      (article #83)
    - "Private Groups vs. Social Justice: The Freedom to be Bad" The Nation, Vol. 216, No. 4, January 22, 1973 (Box 61)
      (article #84)
    - "The Right of Privacy; The Poisonous Tree" The Nation, Vol. 212, No. 8, February 22, 1971 (Box 61)
      (article #85)
    - "How Far Electronic Surveillance" Current, No. 129, May 1971 (Box 61)
      (article #85a)
    - "The Justification of Democracy" The Monist, Vol. 55, No. 1, January 1971 (Box 61)
      (article #86)
    - "Three Tests for an Electorate" The New York Times (Op-Ed), November 4, 1970 (Box 61)
      (article #87)
    - "Citizenship and Obedience: Tangled Obligations" The Nation, Vol. 211, No. 9, September 28, 1970 (Box 61)
      (article #88)
    - "Sex, Birth Control, and Human Life" Ethics, Vol. 79, No. 4, July 1969 (Box 61)